Hey everyone, and thanks for jumping
back into the Forex First.
Today, we're going to talk about the US
dollar currency index, one of the most
riveting topics for everyone here. If
you guys like the content, make sure you
subscribe to the channel, give the video
a thumbs up, and also check out the sale
on ITC premium. Link is in the
description below. Also, be sure to get
your ticket to the first Investing
Through the Cycles conference taking
place November 21st. Let's go ahead and
jump in. So, my views on the dollar
remain unchanged. I would be willing to
pivot my view
if the Fed is unwilling to raise rates.
However,
I think that the Fed will raise rates
again before the end of the year.
I do. And I think there's a chance they
might do it as early as September. And
that's not really a contrarian view at
this point for the Fed to raise rates. I
mean, as of right now, again, I'm going
to be traveling for the next like week
and a half or so. It's currently
September 9th.
You're probably watching this video like
many, many days from now
on the public channel.
But, the odds as of September 9th for a
rate hike are 60%.
If the Fed were to follow through with
this
and actually raise rates, I think you're
going to see the dollar bounce and head
back up. Now, if you zoom in to the
moves by the dollar over the last couple
of lows that have formed, you'll see
there's a pattern, right? It sets a low,
it rallies, it comes back down, and then
goes higher.
Okay, again, look. Sets a low, rallies,
comes back down, and then goes higher.
Same thing, right? Comes down, rallies,
back down,
higher
in my opinion.
This is what I think's going to happen.
By the time you're watching this video,
maybe gold or sorry, maybe maybe the
dollar is no longer at 98. You know, I
don't know what it's going to be by the
time I release the video, but I'm trying
to just pre-record a few videos just so
there's something that I'm putting out
while I'm traveling.
And things like the dollar don't tend to
be nearly as volatile as other assets
like Bitcoin because Bitcoin's moving,
you know, very very very quickly
sometimes and so it's harder to make
videos on it
when I'm going to be gone.
So,
the dollar, the path to me is to head
back up. Okay?
We've talked about this before. If you
look at the the dollar during Trump's
first term and his second term, it's
basically the same path so far, right?
Down for the first year, consolidate,
and then start heading back up. And we
also had a drop in the dollar around
this time during Trump's first term and
you can see that it was only that was on
we're on day 597
indexed to when the administrator or the
new administration
in 2018 the dollar started going up on
day 608.
And it went up into the end of the year.
I think the same thing's going to
happen. Now, if you were to overlay
interest rates onto the chart for the
dollar, right? What you'll notice
we zoom out here.
What you'll notice in 2018, late 2018,
we also
got a rate hike or two.
But, it was different because we were in
the middle of a rate hiking cycle. But
still, the dollar was going up. What's
more accurate in my opinion to compare
to is not 2018 in this case, but to go
back in time and find
a rate hiking cycle
followed by a pause followed by a
cutting cycle, and then what happened
when interest rates went back up. That's
what you should look at.
Not 2018. So,
the 1990s is our example.
Look at what happened.
We had the rate hiking cycle.
We had the rate cutting cycle.
Fed funds rate remains constant.
And then we got a rate hike.
And you can see on that rate hike and
and right before the rate hike occurred,
the dollar started to explode higher.
You see that? It was at like 90 91 just
before the rate hike. And and about a
month or so after the rate hike it was
all the way up at 97.
And it actually continued to go up until
the Fed cut rates again. So, I think
the most likely path for the dollar
is what I'm about to draw.
Something like this.
It finds a low.
Sorry. I need to do the uh
It rallies.
Comes back down. Something like this.
But then eventually
heads back up here.
And then from there
you might see it get rejected again.
Something like that is what I think will
play out for the dollar.
Now,
if the dollar were to take out all these
lows, then I might have to reassess.
This pattern does somewhat look like the
Bitcoin dominance pattern to me
uh from
from the prior cycle, right? So, if you
go look at at Bitcoin and you're like,
"Why is he Why does he always work in
Bitcoin dominance?" Well, if you look at
at Bitcoin dominance in um
you know, over here, there was a period
where you had three lower lows and then
you had a fourth slightly lower low and
then we were back in business.
The reason I don't think this is what's
going to happen and that I think it'll
be a higher low instead is because this
included stable coins, and if you
exclude stable coins from the Bitcoin
dominance chart, which I think is a
relevant exercise to do in order to
truly measure like, you know, what it is
we're we're actually trying to measure,
um
you'll you'll see that it actually looks
completely different, right? So, when
you look at it like this, you'll see
that it was
a higher low.
Consolidate and move up. So, I think the
dollar will find a low soon, and then
it'll move up into the rate hike, and
then likely continue to move up until
the Fed cuts rates again. And what that
means is that the dollar is likely going
to come back up to this trend line.
So, it'll probably tag it, you know,
maybe in 2027 or 2028 around like 104.
104, 105 seems about right.
So, that's what I would look for for the
dollar.
Gold is already sniffing out this
weakness, right? Gold's already going
down right now to try to find a low
that's and maybe even a higher low to to
print. And I I think the reason gold has
been struggling the last few weeks is
because it knows that this rise in the
dollar is about to start.
So, that's my view on the dollar.
Uh if you guys like the content, make
sure you subscribe to the channel, give
the video a thumbs up. Um and again,
check out the sale on ITC Premium at
intothecryptoverse.com.
Would love to see you guys at the first
Investing Through the Cycles conference
taking place in Miami, uh the week uh
the weekend of November 21st. I will see
you guys, hopefully, there.
Bye.